Phumin Walaipatchara

PROFILE

Software engineer with experience in InsurTech, financial application, machine learning, and cloud computation. Past works involve web/APIs development + database management, automated cryptocurrency trading applications, AI models delivery through different solutions such as cloud-native REST APIs or near real-time systems. Experienced cloud computing providers include AWS and Google Cloud Platform.

EDUCATION

Boston University, Boston, MA, USA – BA&MS Computer Science, 2020

Boston University, Boston, MA, USA - Minor Economics, 2020

EXPERIENCES

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, SUNDAY INS.; BANGKOK, THAILAND - 2022 - PRESENT

Full-stack software engineer responsible for web and APIs development to facilitate insurance and retail operations. Also integrate our systems with partners that aim to bundle and automate insurance product sales. Additionally, develop internal tools and solutions for insurance policies/claims management. Some of the technologies frequently used are React, Next.js, Express.js, RDBMS, Docker, and Git. Some of the programming languages frequently used are JavaScript/Node.js/TypeScript.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, QIS CAPITAL (UNDER SERTIS CO., LTD.); BANGKOK, THAILAND - 2021 - 2022

Responsible for pushing trading strategies into actions on a cloud computing provider: adapt PoC code into cloud-native application and implement a continuous testing + cloud deployment with Git repository CI and Cloud Deployment Kit (CDK). Developing internal APIs and maintenance are also a part of the responsibilities to facilitate trading application on cloud computing provider. Some of the technologies frequently used are Docker, CI/CD, and Git. Some of the programming languages frequently used are Python and JavaScript/TypeScript.

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER, SERTIS CO., LTD.; BANGKOK, THAILAND - 2020 - 2021

Software engineer based role involving machine learning models. Do fine-tuned ML models delivery to the customers through different mediums such as REST APIs with cloud computing backends or near real-time solutions located at the deployment locations. Some of the technologies frequently used are Docker, CI/CD, and Git. Some of the programming languages frequently used are Python and TypeScript.

ONLINE TUTOR, CHEGG INC.; BOSTON, MA, USA - 2019

Online tutor responsible for assisting students with homework of problems in Computer Science field.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript/Node.js, TypeScript, HTML/CSS, Python, Java, SQL, Go, C++
- Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Keras, TensorFlow, MXNet, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV
- Frameworks: React, Angular, Next.js, Express.js, FastAPI
- Others: AWS, GCP, Serverless, Docker, CI/CD, Git, Bash, Linux CLI, LaTeX

PHONE:+66 84-015-3486 E-MAIL: PHUMINWAL@GMAIL.COM WEBSITE: PHUMINW.GITHUB.IO

LINKEDIN: LINKEDIN.COM/IN/PHUMINW